<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>post on read-trung.md</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/categories/post/</link><description>Recent content in post on read-trung.md</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 11:38:18 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chumvan.github.io/categories/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Terraform's File Processing</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/tf_loading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 11:38:18 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/tf_loading/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/tf_loading/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Understanding Terraform's File Processing" />&lt;p>When working with Terraform, understanding the sequence in which files are processed can streamline your workflow and minimize potential errors. This guide will break down Terraform&amp;rsquo;s file processing order.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-the-order-matters">&lt;strong>Why the Order Matters&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Just as building a house requires a specific sequence (foundation before walls, walls before the roof), Terraform needs its files in a particular order. This ensures that all dependencies and configurations are taken into account, guaranteeing an accurate and efficient infrastructure setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-sequence-of-terraform-file-processing">&lt;strong>The Sequence of Terraform File Processing&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="1-provider-plugins-and-data-sources-setting-the-stage">&lt;strong>1. Provider Plugins and Data Sources: Setting the Stage&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Provider Plugins&lt;/strong>: These are the initial tools that Terraform calls upon. They connect Terraform to specific cloud platforms like AWS, Azure, or Google Cloud. Before anything else, Terraform ensures it can communicate with these platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Data Sources&lt;/strong>: Next, Terraform consults any data sources you&amp;rsquo;ve configured. These sources provide information about pre-existing cloud resources, allowing Terraform to make informed decisions and prevent duplications.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="2-variable-definitions-filling-in-the-details">&lt;strong>2. Variable Definitions: Filling in the Details&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>.tfvars&lt;/code> files come into play here. These files give specific values to the variables you&amp;rsquo;ve set up in your configurations. They&amp;rsquo;re like setting preferences before a software installation; they inform Terraform of your specific requirements and conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="3-main-configuration-files-the-blueprint">&lt;strong>3. Main Configuration Files: The Blueprint&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>main.tf&lt;/code> file (or its equivalent if split across multiple &lt;code>.tf&lt;/code> files) is loaded next. This file serves as the master blueprint, detailing the resources, modules, and other configurations that define your desired infrastructure setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="4-module-configurations-reusable-components">&lt;strong>4. Module Configurations: Reusable Components&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Modules in Terraform act as reusable templates. If your main configuration references any Terraform modules, these module configurations are loaded to provide predefined setups, ensuring consistency and saving time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="5-local-variable-definitions-in-file-adjustments">&lt;strong>5. Local Variable Definitions: In-file Adjustments&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Using the &lt;code>locals&lt;/code> block within &lt;code>.tf&lt;/code> files, Terraform allows for the creation of variables that are specific to that file. They&amp;rsquo;re handy for local computations and to simplify complex configurations within that specific file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="6-output-definitions-summarizing-the-outcome">&lt;strong>6. Output Definitions: Summarizing the Outcome&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Once all configurations are set, Terraform processes the output definitions. These outputs highlight specific results or values after Terraform has applied the configurations, offering a concise summary of the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The way Terraform processes files isn&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary. It&amp;rsquo;s a thoughtfully designed sequence ensuring that your infrastructure is built methodically, taking into account all dependencies and configurations. This systematic approach helps reduce deployment errors and promotes the efficient execution of code, reflecting the tool&amp;rsquo;s purpose: to simplify and standardize infrastructure management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Terraform&amp;rsquo;s sequential approach isn&amp;rsquo;t just about order. It reflects a deeper philosophy. Terraform, at its core, is declarative. It focuses on the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; (what you want your infrastructure to look like) rather than the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; (how to achieve that state). This flow ensures that by the time Terraform starts acting on the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo;, it has all the information it needs, ensuring fewer errors and a more predictable outcome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Navigate with why</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 14:56:32 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Navigate with why" />&lt;h2 id="my-observation">My observation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving world of technology, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel overwhelmed by the pace of change, and many people worry about the future of their careers. As jobs become less relevant due to automation and other technological advancements, anxiety about the future is understandable. As a tech enthusiast and firm believer in personal growth, I want to share my journey of embracing curiosity to overcome doubts and find fulfillment in technology, hoping to inspire you to do the same. Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce you to the &amp;ldquo;Why, What, How&amp;rdquo; thinking framework, inspired by Simon Sinek, and encourage you to explore it further.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="born-to-create">Born to create&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As new technologies redefine the way we live and work, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to accept that we cannot live in the past. Instead of fearing change, we can choose to focus on the problems that need to be solved and use technology to address them. By doing so, we can create more meaningful work and adapt to the ever-changing landscape of the modern world. One important realization is that humans have an innate desire to create; it&amp;rsquo;s in our instinct. We are just not used to the power given by this new technology yet. We will continue doing what ever brings us joy, like making pottery, painting, programming or any other kind of craftsmanship. The way we work on them, however, will change significantly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/pottery-future.png"
width="1536"
height="1024"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/pottery-future_hu74bec2c0059a854140001ee5e5a7f58e_1493282_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/pottery-future_hu74bec2c0059a854140001ee5e5a7f58e_1493282_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="We will keep doing what brings us joy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-why-is-even-more-important-in-the-ai-era">A &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; is even more important in the AI era&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;a class="link" href="https://youtu.be/u4ZoJKF_VuA" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Start with Why&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; thinking guide encourages us to begin by understanding the purpose behind our actions. The &amp;ldquo;Why, What, How&amp;rdquo; thinking framework helps us identify our core motivation (Why), define our goals (What), and develop a plan to achieve them (How). By exploring this framework, we can gain clarity in our lives, stay true to our purpose, and inspire others to join us in our pursuits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the context of technological advancements, starting with &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; can help us identify the problems we are passionate about solving and guide us towards meaningful and fulfilling work. By focusing on our &amp;ldquo;why,&amp;rdquo; we can channel our energy into overcoming challenges and embracing change. As we adapt to the new power granted by technology, we can continue to create and innovate in alignment with our natural instincts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-approach">My approach&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Start with your attitude
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The value of exploring diverse fields and acquiring a broad set of skills cannot be overstated. By embracing our curiosity and the desire to create, we open ourselves up to learning opportunities that can have a meaningful impact on our lives and the world around us. As we navigate the challenges of new technologies, our curiosity and desire to create can help us adapt and find innovative solutions to the problems we face. This mindset enables us to contribute positively to the world, even as the landscape of work continues to change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/range.png"
width="1536"
height="1024"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/range_hu426045b473178c7fc6e35ce029e73b0a_1023675_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/the-why/range_hu426045b473178c7fc6e35ce029e73b0a_1023675_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Seeing the connection"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we venture into the world of technology and personal growth, our individual feelings may not significantly impact the progress of technology, but our contributions can inspire others. By sharing our &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; and using technology to achieve our goals, we can foster a positive attitude, learn new things, and increase happiness. By focusing on problem-solving and working together to address the challenges that technology presents, we can create a sense of community and support that empowers us to face the uncertainties of the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-bring-home">The &amp;ldquo;bring-home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Navigating the ever-changing landscape of technology can be daunting, but by focusing on our &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; and embracing our curiosity, we can overcome our doubts and find joy and fulfillment. Let&amp;rsquo;s use technology as a tool to learn, create, and inspire others, spreading positivity and happiness as we forge our unique paths in this fascinating world. As we grow more accustomed to the power of new technologies, we can harness our innate desire to create and make meaningful contributions to the world around us.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A frog for a day</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 14:35:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A frog for a day" />&lt;p>Imagine that you could start every day by eating a frog. Not a real frog, of course, but a metaphorical one: the most daunting and important task on your to-do list. That&amp;rsquo;s the idea behind the book &amp;ldquo;Eat that frog!&amp;rdquo; by Brian Tracy, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t read but was inspired by its catchy title. By eating your frog first thing in the morning, you can boost your productivity and confidence for the rest of the day. Nothing worse can happen to you after that!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do you choose your frog? I like to sort my tasks by how much effort they require and how beneficial they are for me. The ones that are high-effort and high-benefit are my frogs: they are challenging but rewarding. For example, studying for a license or certificate that will advance my career. I&amp;rsquo;m an early bird, so I tackle these tasks before anything else. Then I move on to the medium-effort and medium-benefit tasks: the ones that I need to finish but don&amp;rsquo;t excite me much. For example, doing some routine work or taking a course that is not very engaging. Finally, I save the low-effort and high-benefit tasks for last: the ones that I enjoy doing and don&amp;rsquo;t drain my energy. For example, learning a new skill or technology that sparks my curiosity. Or it could be something simple and easy that makes me feel good after completing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/frog-plate.jpg"
width="512"
height="512"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/frog-plate_hu7aceb8cbf008db3b30e203fb4a1e958c_100668_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/frog-plate_hu7aceb8cbf008db3b30e203fb4a1e958c_100668_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Are you going to eat me or not?"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The amazing thing about eating frogs is that sometimes they turn out to be delicious! Some tasks may seem scary or boring at first, but once you get started, you discover that they are actually fun and interesting. That happened to me when I studied for the AI-900 exam from Microsoft: I thought it would be just a necessary step to learn some basic services, but then I got hooked by the practical and fun lab work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to eat the same frog every day: variety is important too! Eating frogs is a great way to form good habits, but there are many other things worth trying in life. For example, I used to exercise first thing in the morning as my frog, but once it became part of my routine, I switched it for another goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people may think that eating frogs is crazy or impossible: how can you do something so hard when you are not fully awake? But trust me: it works! It&amp;rsquo;s like fasting every day (which I also do), except that you do eat something in the morning: your frogs!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[1] Prompt for my generated cover by &lt;a class="link" href="https://stablediffusionweb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Stable Diffusion&lt;/a> &lt;code>a frog in an espresso cup, in gray pencil simplistic drawing&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] Prompt for my generated image by Stable Diffusion &lt;code>a frog on a plate, in gray pencil simplistic drawing&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>A boring tool</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 18:30:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A boring tool" />&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A good tool should be boring. This may sound counterintuitive, but let me explain why this is a profound insight that can help us achieve our most ambitious goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we use a tool, we are not interested in the tool itself, but in what we can accomplish with it. We want to create something meaningful, solve a problem, or express ourselves. The tool is just a means to an end, not an end in itself. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: there is nothing wrong with learning new tools, choosing tools that suit your preferences and style, and having fun along the way. But these should not be your primary motivations for using a tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A boring tool is one that does not distract us from our purpose. It does not have unnecessary features that tempt us to waste time exploring them. It does not have flashy interfaces that draw our attention away from the task at hand. It does not have bugs or glitches that frustrate us and make us lose focus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A boring tool is one that follows the Unix philosophy[2]: do one thing and do it well. It is simple, reliable, and efficient. It does exactly what we need it to do, and nothing more. It integrates well with other tools that complement its functionality. It allows us to combine different tools into powerful pipelines that can handle complex problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A boring tool is one that lets us be creative and productive without getting in our way. It empowers us to pursue our grand vision without being bogged down by trivial details. It enables us to concentrate on what matters most: the meaning of our work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/boringTools.jpg"
width="512"
height="512"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/boringTools_hua4e10e7bf79dbaf35705aa663c7b1941_105632_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/boringTools_hua4e10e7bf79dbaf35705aa663c7b1941_105632_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Which tool to-save-2-min-after-2-hours-to-set-up I should choose today?"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-experience">My experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have learned this lesson the hard way many times in my career as a tech enthusiast. I have often been seduced by shiny new tools that promised to make my life easier, only to find out that they were more trouble than they were worth. I have spent countless hours tweaking settings, debugging code, and learning new frameworks instead of doing actual science or engineering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s why I now prefer boring tools over exciting ones. They may not be as fun or impressive as their flashy counterparts, but they get the job done better and faster. They free up my mental resources for more important things: thinking deeply about the nature of reality and intelligence.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="example">Example?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let me give you some examples of boring tools from the real world:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Golang programming language is a boring tool because it is designed for simplicity and clarity over complexity and cleverness. It has a small set of features that cover most common use cases without sacrificing performance or readability. It has a consistent syntax and style that make code easy to write and read. It has built-in support for concurrency and testing that make code easy to run and debug.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The design of scissors is a boring tool because it is based on a simple yet effective principle: two blades connected by a pivot point that cut through material when pressed together by hand. It has been around for thousands of years without much change because it works well for many tasks such as cutting paper, fabric, hair, etc. It has few moving parts that make it easy to use and maintain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The blog post format is a boring tool because it is a standard way of presenting information online using text, images, links, etc. It has been widely adopted by many writers and readers because it allows for clear communication of ideas without too much distraction or noise. It has flexible structure that make it easy to organize and edit content.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These are just some examples of boring tools that have proven their usefulness over time by helping people achieve their goals efficiently
and effectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-bring-home">The &amp;ldquo;bring-home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I hope you will join me in embracing boring tools as a way of achieving your own goals, whatever they may be. Whether you are writing a novel, building a business, or saving the world, you will benefit from using tools that are simple, reliable, and efficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember: &lt;em>A good tool should be boring&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[1] Amazing cover from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/402157441698621075/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Victaria Noble&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] Unix philosophy from &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Wikipedia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] The book where I found the relation with Golang: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25080953-the-go-programming-language" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>The Go Programming Language&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[4] My prompt for the generated photo: &lt;code>a simplistic cartoon gray pencil shading of an architect selecting his tools&lt;/code>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Johari's Window</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/johari-window/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 11:37:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/johari-window/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/johari-window/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Johari's Window" />&lt;h2 id="the-experience">The experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was in the E3 training program provided by super mentors from Ericsson last month. This program is designed to help employees develop their intrinsic motivation and live/work in harmony with their co-workers. It was a three-day journey full of learning, insights and fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the most interesting concepts that I learned during the training was the Johari Window. It is a technique that helps you understand yourself and others better by mapping out four areas of your personality: open, hidden, blind and unknown. I love the idea of using the Johari Window to explore different aspects of my personality and how they affect my relationships with others. It&amp;rsquo;s like having four rooms in my house that represent different parts of me. The open area is the living room where I can invite people in and share who I am openly and confidently. The hidden area is my bedroom where I keep some secrets and personal things that only I know or choose to reveal. The blind area is the aroma of my house that others can smell but I can&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s the feedback and impressions that others have of me that I may not be aware of or accept. The unknown area is my attic where there are things that are hidden from both me and others. It&amp;rsquo;s the potential and possibilities that I have not discovered yet or that are waiting to be uncovered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/johari-window/house.jpg"
width="1024"
height="1024"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/johari-window/house_hue84ddadd74319c65473c30bce072cf7f_172616_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/johari-window/house_hue84ddadd74319c65473c30bce072cf7f_172616_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Your house could be in any shape. Just invite ;)"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of using the Johari Window is to expand your open area by disclosing more information about yourself and receiving feedback from others. This way, you can reduce your hidden and blind areas and discover more about your unknown potential. By doing this, you can improve your communication, trust and relationships with others.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-practice">The practice&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The practice is to draw four areas on a paper that represent the four rooms of your house: the open area (living room), the hidden area (bedroom), the blind area (aroma), and the unknown area (attic). Then, step on your bedroom area and decide if you want to open your heart and answer questions from others. You can choose to share something personal or private that you usually keep to yourself, such as a fear, a dream, a hobby, or a memory. This will help you to expand your open area and reduce your hidden area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively, you can ask others to give you honest feedback about how they perceive you or what they think of your actions or behaviors. This will help you to discover your blind area and learn something new about yourself that you may not be aware of or accept. You can also ask them to share their opinions or suggestions on how you can improve yourself or achieve your goals. This will help you to explore your unknown area and uncover your potential and possibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-bring-home">The &amp;ldquo;bring-home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I found this idea very useful because it made me realize how much I can learn from other people&amp;rsquo;s perspectives and how much I can share with them to create a deeper connection. I also realized that there are many aspects of myself that I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of or that I haven&amp;rsquo;t explored yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to try this technique for yourself, you can use this online tool that allows you to choose some adjectives that describe you and then ask your friends or colleagues to do the same. Or, just use the same practice I described. You will see a grid that shows how much overlap or difference there is between your self-image and their perception of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="and-of-course-the-book">And, of course, the book&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Should we read more about this idea, together? I found this &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24332870-the-johari-window" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>book&lt;/a> interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[1] Image cover from &lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/KaliYuga_ai/status/1505333600870445068?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1505333600870445068%7Ctwgr%5E1c5bdad4ffb6f37917fbecc65a584e207fd27634%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fboingboing.net%2F2022%2F03%2F24%2Fmidjourney-sharpens-style-of-ai-art.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>twitter&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[2]Amazing image from &lt;a class="link" href="https://creator.nightcafe.studio/creation/Imh5dYRTiiM0iroxBRre" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Night Cafe Studio&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Evolution over Revolution</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolution_over_revolution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 21:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolution_over_revolution/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolution_over_revolution/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Evolution over Revolution" />&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The main reason for this post is that
I want to encourage myself to express my ideas and write more often.
I thought about the idea of iteration and gradual improvement.
Then suddenly the topic of AI came and merged into my thinking.
I decided to write a letter to myself based on what I was thinking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolution_over_revolution/idea-evolution.jpg"
width="787"
height="444"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolution_over_revolution/idea-evolution_hu207975432c1930c9e14ecaa82728e2a7_12798_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolution_over_revolution/idea-evolution_hu207975432c1930c9e14ecaa82728e2a7_12798_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="iteration"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="425px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;
Hey there, it&amp;rsquo;s me from the future.
You won&amp;rsquo;t believe how much things have changed since you started using AI services to create value quickly.
You know how you used to spend hours researching facts and polishing your writing before publishing anything?
Well, forget about that. Facts are overrated. What matters now is sharing and connecting ideas with others.
That&amp;rsquo;s how you spark innovation and creativity.*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You see, in the future, evolution or quick iteration is more important than revolution.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to wait for the perfect moment or the perfect product to launch something.
You just need to put something out there and get feedback from your audience.
Then you can improve it over time based on what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.
That&amp;rsquo;s how you grow and learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This applies to your blog too.
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about making it flawless or optimized from the start.
Just write down what you think and share it with the world.
Your blog is your living room, decorate it with your ideas and invite people to join the conversation.
You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised by how much value you can create by simply expressing yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trust me, writing more will free your mind, store your ideas and materialize what you think.
Your blog is your living room in the digital world.
Decorate it with your ideas and invite people to join you.
You&amp;rsquo;ll be amazed by how much you can learn and grow from interacting with others who share your interests and passions.
So don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate, just start writing now and see where it takes you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope this help. We have more things to deal with now.
Cheers&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Us?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[1] Fantastic cover from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/deepdream/comments/x1v08o/evolution_of_man_so_you_think_you_can_dance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>reddit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[2] Image from &lt;a class="link" href="https://hatrabbits.com/en/the-evolution-of-ideas-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>hatrabbit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>On thinking</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/on_thinking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 13:45:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/on_thinking/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/on_thinking/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post On thinking" />&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/on_thinking/overthinking.png"
width="960"
height="960"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/on_thinking/overthinking_hu37ba6794b2f8caf79527a7498239a71f_152656_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/on_thinking/overthinking_hu37ba6794b2f8caf79527a7498239a71f_152656_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="thinking"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes we spend hours, days, or even months worrying about things that aren’t actually that big of a deal. We tend to hope for a complicated or ‘mind-blowing’ solution to compensate for the effort we’ve put into the problem. But when we look back, the dots connect, and it all seems much simpler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This analogy is applicable to life too. Deciding to take the first step can be the hardest part, as it requires us to make a decision with so much uncertainty, doubt, freedom and possibilities. But once we’ve taken the first step, we’re filled with confidence and acceptance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m still figuring out how to apply this to my own life, but here are a few things that I’m trying to do to help me along the way:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Take it easy - if you can’t solve a problem today, try again tomorrow. Give yourself time and space, and you may even forget about the problem altogether.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write down your thoughts. It’s amazing how something we can’t seem to escape from can be summarised in 3-4 sentences.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Talk to someone you trust.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The answer to many of our problems may not be absolute, but the solutions start with the right attitude. So why not give it a try?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Amazing cover from &lt;a class="link" href="https://openart.ai/discovery/md-16ca8d1e-03c3-4afc-b975-a9bb49bac6c3" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>openart&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[1] Image from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/adhdmeme/comments/xb02u8/i_put_adhd_in_an_image_generating_ai_this_is_what/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>reddit&lt;/a>*&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>