<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thought on read-trung.md</title>
    <link>https://chumvan.github.io/tags/thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thought on read-trung.md</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 14:35:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chumvan.github.io/tags/thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A frog for a day</title>
      <link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 14:35:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/eatthefrog/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you could start every day by eating a frog. Not a real frog, of course, but a metaphorical one: the most daunting and important task on your to-do list. That&amp;rsquo;s the idea behind the book &amp;ldquo;Eat that frog!&amp;rdquo; by Brian Tracy, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t read but was inspired by its catchy title. By eating your frog first thing in the morning, you can boost your productivity and confidence for the rest of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A boring tool</title>
      <link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 18:30:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/boringtool/</guid>
      <description>The statement A good tool should be boring. This may sound counterintuitive, but let me explain why this is a profound insight that can help us achieve our most ambitious goals.
When we use a tool, we are not interested in the tool itself, but in what we can accomplish with it. We want to create something meaningful, solve a problem, or express ourselves. The tool is just a means to an end, not an end in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution over Revolution</title>
      <link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolutionoverrevolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 21:15:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/evolutionoverrevolution/</guid>
      <description>The main reason for this post is that I want to encourage myself to express my ideas and write more often. I thought about the idea of iteration and gradual improvement. Then suddenly the topic of AI came and merged into my thinking. I decided to write a letter to myself based on what I was thinking about.
&amp;quot; Hey there, it&amp;rsquo;s me from the future. You won&amp;rsquo;t believe how much things have changed since you started using AI services to create value quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On thinking</title>
      <link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 13:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we spend hours, days, or even months worrying about things that aren’t actually that big of a deal. We tend to hope for a complicated or ‘mind-blowing’ solution to compensate for the effort we’ve put into the problem. But when we look back, the dots connect, and it all seems much simpler.
This analogy is applicable to life too. Deciding to take the first step can be the hardest part, as it requires us to make a decision with so much uncertainty, doubt, freedom and possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
