<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thought on Trung Van</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/tags/thought/</link><description>Recent content in thought on Trung Van</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 13:45:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chumvan.github.io/tags/thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On thinking</title><link>https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 13:45:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/overthinking.png"
width="960"
height="960"
srcset="https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/overthinking_hu37ba6794b2f8caf79527a7498239a71f_152656_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://chumvan.github.io/post/onthinking/overthinking_hu37ba6794b2f8caf79527a7498239a71f_152656_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="thinking"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes we spend hours, days, or even months worrying about things that aren’t actually that big of a deal. We tend to hope for a complicated or ‘mind-blowing’ solution to compensate for the effort we’ve put into the problem. But when we look back, the dots connect, and it all seems much simpler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This analogy is applicable to life too. Deciding to take the first step can be the hardest part, as it requires us to make a decision with so much uncertainty, doubt, freedom and possibilities. But once we’ve taken the first step, we’re filled with confidence and acceptance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m still figuring out how to apply this to my own life, but here are a few things that I’m trying to do to help me along the way:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Take it easy - if you can’t solve a problem today, try again tomorrow. Give yourself time and space, and you may even forget about the problem altogether.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write down your thoughts. It’s amazing how something we can’t seem to escape from can be summarised in 3-4 sentences.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Talk to someone you trust.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The answer to many of our problems may not be absolute, but the solutions start with the right attitude. So why not give it a try?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[1] Image from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/adhdmeme/comments/xb02u8/i_put_adhd_in_an_image_generating_ai_this_is_what/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>reddit&lt;/a>*&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>